Curriculum Vitae 09.02.2015



## SADI HOSSAIN

Messeniuksenkatu 5 B 38 00250 Helsinki P 050-5291920 sadi.hossain@aalto.fi Mymensingh, Bangladesh - 04.10.1986

## **PROFILE**

I am an open minded and customer oriented student, who thrives in an energetic environment filled with smart, motivated and awesome people. I have been working in a startup environment for the past 1,5 years and have been focusing on front-end development. Currently, I am looking for perspective: how the front-end development workflow in single products is carried out in comparison to consultation and multiple concurrent projects. I want to be challenged, your move.

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Aalto university, fall 2014-Study subject: Computer science; 212/300 cr, 234/300 cr expected by mid-2015

Bachelor of Science, Aalto university, fall 2009 - spring 2015

Study subject: Computer science; 180/180 cr Major: WWW technologies, Minor: Usability

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## Co-founder and Customer Experience, fruitkit, 10/2014 - present

My responsibilities include creating, maintaining and improving the customer order flow, so that not only can our customers enjoy the freshest fruit, but have an excellent experience doing so.

### Web Developer, Coreorient Oy, 06/2013 - present

My work primarily involves with front-end web design and implementation.

Apple Sales Professional and Service Technician, Tekninen Toimisto Tektor Oy, 11/2009 - 05/2013 Primary position at sales and servicing of Apple products, customer service and advising.

# Layout Designer, HYY kehitysyhteistyövaliokunta, 10/2008 - 12/2008

Worked as the layout designer for Kimppu -magazine.

# Other work experience:

District and Local Guard, Group 4 Securicor — 06/2008 - 10/2009

Measuring Assistant, Rakennemittaus A&O — 06/2007 - 10/2007

Reception Assistant, Hilton Kalastajatorppa — 11/2005 - 12/2007

Working as a model for e.g.. Nokia, Hartwall and Yhteisvastuu commercials.

Summer and seasonal employee in Posti Group Oyj (previously Suomen posti Oy) 2003-2004

Curriculum Vitae 09.02.2015

# LANGUAGE SKILLS

Bengali: native Finnish: spoken: excellent, written excellent Swedish: fair French: basics

### IT-SKILLS

## **Programming:**

JavaScript (professional level) – AngularJS, NodeJS, Express, Bootstrap Python (advanced level) – Django, Flask Java (average level) C (basic level)

## Methodologies:

Agile developmental practices: Test driven development, Scrum, Pair programming

CVS: git, git-flow

Development tools: npm, bower, yo, grunt, gulp

Deployment: Heroku, AWS

CMS: Wordpress

### Operating systems:

Mac OS X (OS of choice), Linux, Windows

## EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Support Student, The English School High School — 2002 - 2003

Tutor, The English School High School — 2004 - 2005

Student Union Treasurer, The English School High School — 2005 - 2006

Sössö -magazine Senior Layout Designer, Guild of Electrical Engineers — 2007 - 2009

Vice Chairman, Wiipurilaisen osakunnan laulajat (WiOL) choir — mid-2013 - present

#### MILITARY SERVICE

Pori Brigade, Finnish Rapid Deployment Forces — 07/2010 - 07/2011

# HOBBIES

As a contrast to studying and working I relax by singing and occasionally playing the guitar. Since January 2012 I attend the Wiipurilaisen osakunnan laulajat (WiOL) choir, where I have been the vice chairman of the board since July 2013. I try to keep fit by jogging and playing badminton with my friends. I also enjoy photography, especially with company. My spare time, whenever I can gather some, goes into pet web projects.